# **MAX MURPHY**

Detroit, MI | 810-820-1908 | maxmurphymi@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Full Stack Developer with experience in JavaScript, ReactJS, and Ruby on Rails. Professional experience in audio engineering/production that includes Avid Pro Tools, Adobe Audition, and Logic Pro X. Excited to contribute my success and aptitude in artistic sound engineering to create innovative solutions using new technologies.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming: JavaScript, React, Ruby, HTML, CSS, SQL

Tools: React.is, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, DSA, OOP, Relational Databases, Git, Heroku, Firebase, p5.is

Audio: DAWs - Avid Pro Tools, Adobe Audition, Logic Pro X

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

Hopper's Books - Flatiron School Final Project - Github | Live

Secure Rails/React app for an eCommerce site for a frog-themed bookstore.

- Developed front-end using React.is, and CSS to create a streamlined user experience
- Built PostgreSQL relational database, backend/Rails API structure, and dynamic seeding following the MVC framework
- Dynamically rendered search page book data based on Google Books API endpoints
- Utilized a many-to-many table association for individual user wishlist and purchase data

Spats - Spotify Stats - Flatiron School Project Github | Demo | Live

React/Rails app for viewing your top tracks and artists on Spotify.

- Integrated a React UI with the Spotify for Developer's Web API to provide users with on-demand listening data.
- Compiled listening stats into seed data to create novel music recommendations based on user statistics.

Extraterrestrial Twinning (E.T.T.) - Flatiron School Project - Github | Live

React app featuring a space-themed card-matching game.

- Developed front-end using React is, and CSS to create a streamlined user experience
- Built out card randomization with matching functionality, as well as corresponding score and timer components

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Impact 89fm East Lansing, MI **Production Director** 09/2018 - 05/2020

- Utilized DAWs (Digital Audio Workstations) to produce weekly promos, PSAs, and other on-air content
- Directed weekly volunteer meetings (of 12-15 participants) to facilitate understanding of audio production
- Assisted in the production and broadcast of weekly live in-studio music performances
- Established a welcoming atmosphere for music lovers as a daytime radio DJ

Mac's Bar Lansing, MI **Sound Technician** 08/2019 - 03/2020

- Managed and implemented audio recording and mixing equipment to run live sound for a 112 capacity venue
- Set stage and sound in time-sensitive settings with efficiency to ensure timeliness of event

# **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** Remote 03/2022 - 07/2022

Certification - Software Engineering - Full Stack Web Development

**Michigan State University** 

East Lansing, MI

Bachelor of Art (BA) - Media and Information | Minor: Leadership of Organizations

05/2020